Heliopolis, Ain shams Cairo, Egypt

# MUHAMMED AHMED JAVA BACKEND DEVELOPER

+201220331501 muhammedmady100@gmail.com

PORTFOLIO | GITHUB | LINKEDIN LEETCODE | HACKERRANK

#### **S**UMMARY

I am a passionate software engineer with expertise in problem-solving and website development using Java and the Spring framework. With 2 years of experience as a security researcher, I have successfully uncovered and addressed security vulnerabilities in web applications for leading companies such as PayPal, BMW, Uber, Ford, Sony, and Rapyd.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Java Developer

# **Egabi Solutions**

August 2023 - Present

- Collaborated with my team to develop the criminal justice department's service used by thousands of employees and served millions of people.
- Integrated the criminal justice department's service with other departments, such as Medical Jurisprudence, Egypt Post, and Civil Registration, using Spring Boot and Angular.
- provided expert support in developing and implementing effective technical solutions.

# **Security Researcher**

## Hackerone

March 2021 - August 2023

- Conducted security assessments and vulnerability testing on web applications and systems.
- Collaborated with development teams and security professionals to remediate identified vulnerabilities in a timely and efficient manner.
- Documented findings and provided detailed reports to clients outlining identified vulnerabilities and recommended remediation measures.

#### SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java, TypeScript, Bash.
- Frameworks: Spring boot, Spring Security, Hibernate, Angular.
- Tools: GIT, Linux, Docker.
- Databases: PostgreSQL, Oracle, MYSQL.

#### **PROJECTS**

Café Management System | GitHub

Spring Boot, Spring Security, Angular.

- A website that enables the user to manage their orders and pay bills seamlessly, the website
  provides full functionality to the admin, allowing them to view and delete orders and bills as
  needed.
- ONLINE BANKING | GitHub

Spring Boot, Spring Security, JSP.

 A website allows users to streamline financial processes such as withdrawals, deposits, and transfers.

# **EDUCATION**

# October, Egypt

# **October 6 University**

October 2017 – July 2021

- B.S.E. in Computer Science and Information technology. In-major GPA: 2.96.
- Graduate Project: A smart Parking System designed and implemented using IoT sensors and a web app interface. The system efficiently detects and updates the availability of parking slots in real time, allowing drivers to locate and reserve a parking spot easily.

# **LANGUAGES**

Arabic: Native.English: Fluent.